Hi, and that's awesome, we will go through edit mode in his half copy of it.
To enable edit mode, you need to choose this drop-down and click to the edit.
And you'll see welcome in message what you can do with edit mode.
But I will explain you, you can use the edit mode directly apply edits across multiple files you have in your application,
like in your code-based, based on your chat prompt, so you can ask to work with some files with multiple files.
So edit also apply directly in the detail you don't need to first look at the internet and then click apply like it with ask mode,
so you will apply immediately and you'll see the difference in your files in place.
And you can same accept or decline all these changes.
You can also provide the relevant context right here to the edit mode, but we will explain you in separate lesson of this course.
So let's now go quickly through the popular use cases of the edit mode.
The first type of task you can do is refactoring, you can refer to part of your code.
For example, if you have an application you use use effect hook, I guess you'll face with some renders and you can ask to file it.
Okay, refactors this use effect, the word unnecessary renders and it will suggest you some ideas and of course the example of the code how it can be fixed.
You can ask convert some class components to functional components using hooks.
If you have all direct version and you can create this in U1, like you can add a new feature, you can ask, add me a login form with validation using red hook form.
For example, to this page and it will create the whole logic for you.
We will also install the library and provide the validation example, so you can just need to review it and apply.
I can also ask, implement the dark mode toggle using red context or state management for your application.
It will also do the work but be careful because if the application is too big, it might miss some files to edit and it's always your responsibility to apply the code and do some changes.
You can also pick the bugs. For example, if you have a crash of application because some variable is undefined or user undefined, you can ask, but you need just provide a context specifically what is undefined and when you want to fix and in what component.
You can also ask help with handling an empty state for the least, like if there is least empty, mustn't displayed, you can ask, okay, this with some text instead of empty state.
You can ask, write some unit tests. For example, if you have a button component, you can ask, okay, write some test for the button components using with test library and also rec test on library.
If you know what library is to use, if you don't specify the library, it will use some libraries by default, which is popular also.
After you can ask to test some custom hooks, you can ask about improvements to performance, like optimize rendering of large list using use memo and use code back hooks in the React.
This hooks do some memorization and optimize some performance. You can also ask about some optimization with API calls if you need to implement, promise all or sync await or you need to implement the error handling, like a power can do it for you and apply all the code.
This is how we can use the compiled edit mode to do edits across multiple files.
Now let's look into interface and do some actions.
For example, imagine we want to rename the button component, but you're not expecting how to use the context because we need to rename it into files.
We can just open two files, one close each other, and compile it, shoot or name it in both files.
So we can ask a rename my component, rename my button component to the button component.
Okay, our name my button component in the button in main button file and also in the test file.
Let's see how we'll do this work. You see it's working on a button component. If you have a test file example, similar, you should also rename it.
It provides the test file if you want to do changes. Okay, it was a bit lazy. Let's ask a do same for test file.
Okay, it found the file and also did the renaming right here.
You can go through all the changes using these arrows that you'll also switch through the files. You can also see the files which were changed with these indicators from compiled.
You can save applied changes one by one or you can apply everything together.
The small difference between ask mode that when you keep all the changes for files, you can also undo the changes. I like right here in a chat history. If I do last request, you'll see your button was renamed as previously and the request was disappeared from a chat.
But you can now apply it again and you see it was updated. But of course, we did a mistake and a letter on how it looked like. Let's undo it and ask our name.
And name my button component in the bottom. I should do it correctly. Okay, now you see did it for both files same time. So we can apply everything like clicking on keep here and you see it's all the least of the files changed.
And it's applied. It's fine. Also, if you, for example, have a long history of changes and you want to decline everything you asked to do in this chat, you can hover here at the top and you see the close icon when you click on it.
You see our confirmation dialog that you really want to remove also sequined requests and then do edits made to files in the work and set you click yes and you see everything was reverted.
And I hope it was useful for you and I'm waiting you in the next lesson where I will explain you the most popular mode the aftermath of file it.